# IQBAL ANWAR

## Full-Stack Software Developer

iqbalaanwar@gmail.com ◆ linkedin.com/in/iqbalaanwar ◆ 347-920-8286 github.com/iqbalanwar ◆ iqbalanwar.github.io

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

As an applied math student turned Software Engineer, my statistical analysis knowledge combined with functional programming builds quality, scalable applications. Driven to build useful software, I simplify consumers' complicated routines. With my experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Java, I write efficient and elegant programming solutions.

#### SKILLS

### Programming:

- Front end: JavaScript (ES6), CSS3. HTML5, Bootstrap, React.js
- Back-end: Java, Spring Boot (MVC), SQL (Postgres), MongoDB, unit testing, AWS
- Extra: GitHub, C++, Matlab, Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices

#### General:

- **Microsoft software:** Office (Excel, Access, Powerpoint), Azure
- Project Management: SCRUM (Agile Methodology), JIRA
- Extra: AnyDesk for remote work

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AmEx Developer Academy General Assembly Aug 2019 - Nov 2019

- One of 25 from 1200 applicants accepted into a General Assembly Initiative sponsored by American Express
- Created web applications in collaborative teams using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Java, Spring Boot, SQL, Git, and GitHub
- Learned about Docker (and Kubernetes) for code management, and SCRUM (and Agile) for project management.

Software Developer MOI Inc.

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

• Built a responsive website, moitime.com, using HTML/CSS/jQuery, Bootstrap for front-end; Ruby on Rails and MongoDB for back-end

- Managed workflow using GitHub to share code and website materials
- Planned goals and deadlines for a development and design team using JIRA

Instructor Optimum Tutorial Jan 2014 - July 2015

- Coordinated with schools, other instructors, and teachers to develop teaching methods and integrated instruction best suited for students
- Guided students in their studies, across several subjects and grades. As a result, more than 10 students received above 1800 on their SAT

Social Media Intern Illustriam LLC. Sep 2013 - Jan 2014

- Implemented search engine optimization tactics to increase following on Twitter, Facebook, and Google
- Collaborated closely with other interns and coordinator to build quizzes and tutorials on the website lifegpa.net

## EDUCATION

CUNY City College of New York Major: Applied Mathematics Minor: Computer Science

Minor: Computer Science Graduation: May 2019

General Assembly
American Express Developer Academy

Completion: November 2019